There’s one thing for certain – we’re all getting older.
有一件事是肯定的——我们都在慢慢变老。
And while the older amongst us may be no spring chickens any more, growing old gracefully is no bad thing.
虽然我们当中的年长者早已不再年轻，但优雅地老去并非坏事，毕竟岁月会赋予人智慧。
And with age comes wisdom. However, as the world population ages, will there be enough people to replace our younger selves?
然而，随着全球人口老龄化程度加深，未来会有足够的年轻人来接替我们吗？
A situation where there are more old people than young certainly has an effect on the world.
老年人口数量超过年轻人口，这种情况必然会对世界产生影响。
A report by the Pew Research Center says that globally the number of people over 65 years old will triple by 2050, drastically altering some countries’ demographic make-up.
皮尤研究中心的一份报告指出，到2050年，全球65岁以上的人口数量将增至三倍，这会彻底改变一些国家的人口结构。
This growing and dependent population means that there is an increased demand for health and social care.
这类数量日益增长的受扶养人口，意味着对医疗和社会保障服务的需求会增加。
Governments will struggle to provide satisfactory pensions, which are ultimately funded by taxes paid by the working population.
各国政府将努力提供令人满意的养老金，毕竟养老金的资金最终来自就业人群缴纳的税收。
And long-term, a smaller population of economically-active people may be a problem for companies trying to recruit staff.
从长远来看，劳动适龄人口的减少，可能会给企业招聘员工带来难题。
Attitudes to an ageing population vary around the world.
世界各地对人口老龄化的态度不尽相同。
The Pew Research Center survey found that 87% of Japanese people were most concerned about it, while only 26% of people from the USA were.
皮尤研究中心的调查显示，87%的日本人对此最为担忧，而美国仅有26%的人关注这一问题。
Here, immigration is helping to boost the younger workforce.
在美国，移民正助力扩充年轻劳动力群体。
Some countries thought the elderly should take care of themselves, while others thought it was the responsibility of the family. Many thought the government should be responsible.
有些国家认为老年人应该自理，有些国家则认为赡养老人是家庭的责任，还有很多人认为政府应该负责。
But old age shouldn’t just be seen negatively.
当然，我们不应只从负面视角看待老龄化。
Elderly people have knowledge and experience they can pass on. Some have wealth which they can spend, helping the economy. And some help society by doing voluntary or charity work.
老年人拥有可以传承的知识和经验，部分老年人有可支配的财富，消费后能推动经济发展，还有些老年人会通过志愿服务或慈善活动为社会贡献力量。
Of course, solutions are needed to tackle the issue, and these include increasing the retirement age, encouraging people to save for the future, persuading skilled and educated migrants to fill labour shortages, or even convincing people to have more children.
要解决人口老龄化问题，自然需要找到对应的方案，比如提高退休年龄、鼓励人们为未来储蓄、劝导技术型和高学历移民来填补劳动力缺口，甚至鼓励人们生育更多子女。